[Meet Yourself]
[Episode 04]
You don't go to school.
Do you really plan to raise horses
in your hometown?
I've made up my mind.
When I come of age next year,
I'll ask Aunt Baoping to
introduce a girlfriend to me.
And then,
I'll be together with her for a few years.
When I reach the marriageable age,
I'll marry her.
In this case,
granny can have her great-grandson early.
Then what comes after birth?
Do your child continue to help you raise horses?
After birth,
he or she will be sent to Kunming
to be raised by my father.
So he has something to do when he's free.
Kill two birds with one stone.
Wanna kick me, right?
Come on.
You want to kick me?
Come here.
Kick me.
Here.
Kick me hard.
Come kick me.
I'm not going to school.
I want freedom.
Come and kick me.
Kick me.
Kick me!
Come on!
Yuan.
I'm not going to school.
I want freedom.
Yuan.
You made brother angry again?
Xiaxia, you're here.
Granny.
We're waiting for you to have dinner.
Ham for you.
Such a good ham.
Come here tomorrow.
I'll cook it for you.
Thank you, Granny.
What's wrong, Yuan?
He wants to kick me back to Kunming.
Brother, you kick him out again?
He doesn't like studying.
You force him, and he'll suffer.
It's also a waste of money for our family.
That's it.
Shut up.
Yuan's issue,
let's put it aside.
Xiaxia,
I invite you to come over for dinner today
just to ask about your friend in Shanghai.
My mom came to you again?
Don't blame your mother.
She's worried about you.
My elder sister went to college.
So my mom thinks that
she's right about everything.
I only graduated from junior high school.
When my elder sister says I'm wrong,
my mother thinks I'm wrong.
Then tell me the truth.
What will you do to go to Shanghai?
Just to travel around.
In my life,
the farthest place I've been to is Kunming.
I forgot it because it was in my childhood.
You just travel there.
Don't you look for a job?
I'll go and see it first.
Then do you go there to find a job?
You have learned wood carving for so long.
When my uncle was drunk a few days ago,
he said your skills got better and better.
It's not easy to learn a skill.
Is it so easy to give up?
No.
Kaiwen told me.
And he's my friend in Shanghai.
He has friends in Shanghai
who opened a wood carving studio.
He could introduce me to the interview.
I'll see if it's okay.
His friend opened a wood carving studio.
Then what is he doing?
He runs a homestay.
Recently, he went to Tonglu on business.
He said that when he finished his work,
he'd let me go to Shanghai
and stay in his house.
This is him.
The middle one.
He looks like at your age.
He's two years older than me.
And he's much better than me.
How did you know each other?
I made live-streaming when working.
I have few audiences.
Only he gave me a reward.
Later, my master caught me.
He said I didn't focus on my job.
Then I stopped it.
Brother, don't always regard me as a child.
I'm 22.
I just want to go out and look around.
Then how do you plan to tell your master?
I say I'd just travel there for a couple of days.
And the job,
they don't necessarily want me.
My master has been angry recently.
Don't make excuses.
If you do have the idea of going out
and looking for a job,
you should tell uncle clearly.
This is the least respect for him.
And the woodcarving workshop
can also arrange other workers.
Okay, I see.
As for your mother,
I'll talk to her.
Eat first.
Thank you, brother.
Yes, that's great, Xiaxia!
Remember to bring me a gift.
No problem.
Eat.
Granny, what are you doing?
Come to dinner.
I'm frying some milk cakes.
No need to fry them, Granny.
It's enough.
Granny, come here for dinner.
Granny.
Right away.
You two eat first.
I'll help.
Okay.
Brother, this is very delicious.
Try it.
Granny.
Let me help you.
Did he kick you?
He dare not kick me.
Yao.
Alright.
Then I know.
Is he back now?
He's not arrived yet.
Okay, then I got it.
Rest early.
Alright.
Is that you, Xiaxia?
Sit here.
Well,
Yao called me
and told me to let you go.
Since your brother has said that,
I won't stop you.
Are you still angry?
I'm not angry.
I'm just worried.
In my whole life,
not to mention Shanghai,
I've not even been to the provincial capital.
You go so far this time,
traveling by planes and trains.
I'm just worried.
Yao also told me that
you are an adult now.
He asked me not to treat you like a child.
Since you have that idea
to go to the big city,
I should let you go.
I just think that
I'm sorry for your master.
He has been guiding you for five or six years.
You're about to get to work.
And you leave now.
When we meet in the village,
it's embarrassing.
Don't worry about the family.
And you don't have to think about
sending money home.
I work in the warehouse.
That salary is enough.
It's just you.
The outside is not as good as home,
where there is a hot meal waiting at the door.
When you're outside,
everything is on your own.
I heard people say that
there are not all good people outside.
You're artless.
I'm afraid others will bully you.
I'm afraid you'll go down the wrong path.
Auntie Feng's son,
Xie Qiang,
was such a good boy.
Then he went out with the bad guys
and didn't follow the right path.
He ended up in jail.
That's all.
Pour the water for me.
Don't just pour it out. Pour into the bucket.
I'll flush the toilet with it.
Mom,
I'll make a lot of money in the future
and buy you a big house in the city.
Near the hospital. Everything is around.
Just wait.
I'm not used to living here.
Take your wife to live there.
Your family has so many talents.
Yuan is not enough.
There's also Xiaxia.
Xiaxia is different from Yuan.
Xiaxia is thoughtful since his childhood.
His father left early.
Aunt Baoping brought up two children
all by herself.
Xiaochun is older.
He knew to help the family
wash clothes and cook.
Xiaxia was only eight or nine years old.
And he followed a bunch of uncles
to the mountain to collect mushrooms
and sell them.
Cerebral Haemorrhage before
was an incurable emergency.
Uncle Zeqing was sent to the city hospital
by tractors.
It's delayed on the way.
If this hospital was closed,
maybe he could be saved.
Your dad used to consider about
sending Yuan to their hometown
to raise horses.
Let him suffer
and know that life is not easy.
And he must be willing to
go back to school.
It's all right now.
He's addicted to raising horses.
I'm having a headache.
A little trouble makes him want to quit.
What's the matter?
Isn't he poor at learning?
Right, he can't learn.
Guobao,
you've been playing for ten minutes.
Stop playing.
Let me play for a while more.
You are too young
to play games.
Play games.
It's harmful to your eyes.
Can you write your name now?
Idiot.
Daddy.
Hit her.
Playing all day long.
And you.
Guobao is still under five.
And she puts on glasses.
Don't you manage her?
She's not noisy
only when she plays with the phone.
Are you?
Let me see your little glasses.
You're lovely with glasses,
right?
Cute, right?
You should get married and have a baby.
It's interesting to have a kid.
Is it?
Guobao, call me daddy.
Daddy.
Kiss your daddy.
If your sister-in-law hears,
she'll come out and kick you to death.
Guobao, don't play with the phone.
How about playing games with daddy?
Why did you get up?
Can't sleep?
I slept a lot in the afternoon.
You didn't sleep, too.
Do you want to eat?
I'm not hungry, thanks.
You'll be hungry soon.
I have experience.
I'll get the dishes.
Let's eat together.
Enough chili?
Add more.
Do you want chili, Hongdou?
A little.
Thank you.
Damai,
your noodle is so delicious.
You can open a restaurant.
It requires no skills.
Whatever ingredients I have,
I just throw them into the pot
and boil them together.
With the same ingredients,
some people can cook well,
others can't.
I'm the one who can't cook it well.
Damai's cooking is delicious.
But she doesn't wash the dishes.
I'm not cooking well.
But I can do the dishes.
So every time I want night snacks,
I just call her.
Meal buddies.
Hongdou, how about your cooking?
Not good.
I'm busy with my work.
And I don't cook much.
The kitchen in the apartment
is small and smelly.
What do you do for a living?
I was working at the hotel's Front Office.
Front Office?
It's... Lobby Manager.
I was in charge of catering, guest rooms,
and the executive lounge.
Coordinate among departments
and provide better service for guests.
Awesome.
What's awesome about that?
I got promoted by virtue of seniority.
After all, my age was there.
Very awesome.
After I graduated from college,
I've never worked in the office.
Freelance?
What do you do?
Damai is an online writer.
She works at home normally.
Writer.
It's my first time meeting a writer.
Just a small online writer sitting at home.
I have neither representative works
nor sense of existence.
A transparent one whose existence
is meaningless to the world.
How can you say that?
Online writers are amazing.
Unlike me,
when I write an 800-word composition,
I need punctuation to reach the word count.
Where can I read your novel?
I want to appreciate it.
I... I think...
I think there's no need to read it.
I don't write well.
And I don't want to lose my vest.
Wait till I write a good one.
I'll send it to you then.
Lose the vest?
Lose her online alias.
I won't ask.
What about Nana?
I was a cashier in a coffee shop in Shanghai.
Later, they laid off employees.
So I drove to Yunnan.
I came here by chance.
I really liked it.
So I stayed here to work.
[Card]
Please take out your cash.
Please take out your card.
You only need to change the screen.
The content in the phone won't disappear, right?
No, the motherboard is not broken,
Don't worry.
There is no screen in my store.
It needs to be sent here.
Please leave a number for me.
I'll call you after it is repaired.
I don't have a cell phone.
Or you can leave me a number.
I'll call you.
Here's a business card.
It takes about three days.
Okay.
Do you have an alarm clock or something?
No.
What about a watch?
No, either.
No one buys that, so I don't order.
You can set the alarm clock
with your cell phone.
It's convenient.
The phone is broken and in repair.
How much is it?
86 yuan.
How long will you stay here?
Three months.
Do you come to learn embroidery?
No.
Just traveling.
Here's your change, 14 yuan.
You knew Yao before?
No.
Then he let you ride Lil Cute.
I stepped on horse dung.
I'll step on horse dung next time.
Forget it.
My name is Xiaoqin. What's your name?
Xu Hongdou.
So fancy.
I also have a fancy name.
I picked it up myself.
Don't you ask me what my name is?
What's your name?
My name is Candy.
Candy.
How about it? Fancy, right?
Fancy.
You're busy. I'll go first.
Come and play when you are free.
Okay.
Xiaxia.
Didn't you go to Guangzhou?
Not yet.
My dad asked me to come
to say goodbye to the master.
Stop!
I'll go first.
Come back!
Take it back!
You don't stay in the woodcarving workshop.
What are you doing here?
Yeah, right.
Take all these
and return them.
Tell their families.
Don't come again during festivals.
Go ahead.
Shall I go?
Of course you!
Hurry up and tidy up.
Why do you come to me?
Nothing, master.
Let's talk about it tomorrow.
Tell me, don't hesitate.
Say it!
Master, I just...
I want to travel to Shanghai for some days.
And see if I can find a job over there.
I heard from friends in Shanghai that
The wood carving studio over there is recruiting.
I've never been anywhere else.
I just want to have a look.
They may not accept me.
Master, don't be angry.
Go ahead.
My little temple can't hold
you great Bodhisattva.
Go ahead.
[Express Waybills, Dali to Zibo]
♫ Listen to the rain
falling into the silent forest ♫
♫ Enjoy the mountainous landscape at sunset ♫
[Express Waybills, Dali to Nanjing]
♫ The raindrops on the roof
fall into the eyes secretly ♫
♫ The world is like a quiet island ♫
♫ The sky is turning bright silently ♫
It must be able to get out.
I don't think it can get out.
Come on, ants.
Be brave.
I said they couldn't come out.
Why can't they come out?
Just run out with nose pinched.
Tuotuo.
It's you.
We meet again.
Is this your friend?
Yeah, he's called Huzi.
Hello, Huzi.
Who is she?
She's a new friend I just met.
I don't know who she is.
My name is Xu Hongdou.
You can also call me Aunt Hongdou.
You're not an aunt.
You are a sister.
Your mother and I are of the same generation.
You should call me aunt.
My mom said someone old like this
can be called aunt.
Look, it's still circling.
Come on, ants.
[Receipt for a Loan of Tuotuo's telephone watch]
Sister Hongdou,
I'll go to play with you some other day.
Okay, Bye.
Bye.
Thank you, Sister Hongdou.
♫ The reflection of clouds, the changing moon
and the stars all over the sky ♫
♫ The lost footsteps will be gradually erased ♫
♫ The light and shadow of four seasons ♫
♫ I've seen the meteor
that lights up the night sky ♫
♫ When the wind rises,
the sky will be cloudless ♫
♫ Go to a windy place to meet you ♫
Miss Xu.
Mr. Ma.
Have some tea?
Sure.
Let's go.
Pu'er tea or black tea?
I'm fine with both.
That's the hardest type to serve.
Pu'er Tea.
Are you bored?
No.
You've just read dozens of pages.
The phone is of more fun, right?
Yes.
But,
I can't play it all the time.
It's bad for the eyes.
And I will feel empty.
When the human's brain is stimulated,
it will produce a strong reaction.
The excitement threshold will be
higher and higher.
Emotional control will get worse.
So,
when you put down your phone,
you'll feel empty,
and boring.
Then your emotions
will be excited and irritable.
Over the course of time,
you'll be screwed up.
Can I still be saved?
Meditate.
What do you think when meditating?
At the beginning of meditation,
you have to learn to control yourself.
Throw away all the distractions in your heart.
Focus all your attention on your breath.
What to do after focusing on breathing?
Just concentrate here.
That's it?
That's it.
It's better if you don't understand.
Look at the tea.
You want to say that
even tea goes through trials and tribulations.
It needs to be fermented for a long time
to become tea.
In this world,
everything needs to practice.
Right?
I mean...
The tea infusion is ruddy and shiny.
It's ready to drink.
Thank you.
Won't you answer it?
No need.
It's tea time.
Nothing else is important.
However,
it's a little annoying.
My apology.
The teacup is a little small.
Give me more.
Tea needs to be tasted.
Okay.
When will Mr. Li go to Shuhe River?
I will go too.
Then,
make an appointment for me.
This woodcarving workshop is not your business.
Why do you care so much?
You even go there yourself.
It's within my ability.
I'll help if I can.
After all, I call him uncle.
Right?
I can just stand by and watch
the woodcarving workshop get closed down.
Alright.
When Mr. Li decides the time to come,
I'll tell you.
Thanks, buddy.
You're welcome.
Let's chat when we meet someday.
Bye.
Okay.
My Mr. Xie.
You took care of all these things.
Aren't you tired?
You got a deal for him.
That eases the symptoms,
but not cures the disease.
He doesn't listen to you.
You said to help him for free.
He guarded against you just like a thief.
He's not guarding against me.
He just thinks that publicity
is like every potter praises his own pot.
It is shameless to brag.
You show excessive passion to someone cold.
It's okay.
He will feel the warmth
if I show him more times.
I like this in you very much.
Trying to warm someone cold?
Thick-skinned, just like me.
Thick-skinned.
Our new Tie-Dye Painting details page,
have you designed it?
Almost.
I've just finished
the design of the green plum packing box.
Isn't it the day before yesterday?
I'd better go back and do cross-talk.
Look,
even Landlord Zhou Bapi
made the cock crow until midnight.
You just don't let the cock sleep.
Doesn't designing take time?
The design of the green plum packing box
just made some change
of the ugly apple's design.
You should hurry up.
On my side, the pre-sale promotion plans of
Tie-Dye Paintings and green plums
have been finished.
Just wait for your picture
to post them on our official account.
Alright, Madam.
I'm wrong. My bad.
You are too lazy to do crosstalk.
Begging on the overpass,
and I'm afraid you'll be starving.
We northerners
won't bully those northerners.
Don't make small groups with me.
Hello?
Hello.
Right.
Okay.
Xu Hongdou.
Your mother can't find you.
She calls me here.
My mother can't find me?
Call her back soon.
She sounds very anxious.
Here.
Thank you.
Mr. Xie.
Have some tea?
Sure.
Hello, Mom.
What's up?
Gang and his family
want to travel to Beijing.
You can apply for the preferential price
for employees.
A 20% discount, right?
How much is it with a 20% discount?
More than nine hundred.
Sister, let me talk to Hongdou.
Let Aunt Sun talk with you.
I'm Aunt Sun, Hongdou.
Aunt Sun.
Actually, Gang and his wife
don't have to live in our hotel.
Beijing's transportation is very convenient.
The subway is also efficient.
Well, Dou,
it's because you are in Beijing.
Right?
Then we live in the hotel because of you.
I mean, you are Manager,
big leader or something.
Can you make it cheaper?
Unfortunately,
I'm on vacation in Yunnan.
I can't receive them.
Besides, the hotel price
is not my decision.
I can't change it.
Well, then, otherwise,
tell me the price range you can accept,
let me ask other friends in the hotel industry.
Ask them to recommend
a cost-effective one for you.
Five hundred?
Five hundred, right?
Got it.
Let me help you choose.
Okay.
Thank you, Hongdou.
Thank you, Dou.
Come back often then.
Aunt Sun will make delicious food for you,
all right?
You can talk to your mother.
Okay.
Dou.
how's your trip these days?
Very good.
We're in the yard with friends.
Drink tea or something.
Have you repaired your phone?
I can't contact you.
I'm worried.
What are you worrying about?
You don't call me every day.
It's one thing whether I call or not.
It's another thing that
I can't get in touch with you.
I got it repaired.
I'll get it in two days.
That's good.
Then you play.
I'll hang up.
Look at you.
Your two daughters,
how did you cultivate them?
Both are successful.
Before, my Gang
was in the same class with your Hongmi.
You remember it, right?
Yes.
One was the tail,
and the other was the head.
It's...
Gang is also great now.
He took his father's position
in the fertilizer factory,
and just lives in the next building.
If he wants to have dumplings,
just say it aloud at the window.
Unlike my children,
year after year,
I can't even see them.
It depends.
Look at the phone now.
How convenient!
It can also make video calls.
No matter how far away,
it's the same.
It's the same.
Alright.
You didn't talk to your family
about your resignation?
I'm afraid they would worry if I tell them.
Is there anything wrong with your work?
No.
Then you just don't want to work anymore?
Not really.
All these years.
Day after day.
I'm a little tired.
Did you usually have no rest?
Our industry is a little special.
Even when you rest,
you also need to reply to messages
and make calls to customers.
You can't relax.
So usually,
when I was off duty,
I just wanted to lie down.
Got it.
The workers have no life.
Life is all elsewhere.
In front of us,
everything is mundane.
Here is elsewhere.
You've come to the right place.
The air is good in our Yunnan,
South of Colorful Clouds.
No pollution.
You can go out more.
Have a sunbath and taste good food.
Staying for three months, and you are sure to
have all your spirit recovered.
How long has Mr. Ma been here?
Less than one year.
He has absorbed the essence
of the sun and the moon.
He's about to mutate.
There is atavism.
He doesn't talk normally.
No wonder he's annoying.
About the annoying thing,
the ancients said,
there are no rules for external things.
[Li Hao]
Sorry.
I need to answer the phone.
Hello, old schoolmate.
Right.
The matter of transferring a student.
The student's academic status
and registered residence are in Kunming.
Please ask it for me first.
Okay.
I'll wait for your message.
I'll treat you someday.
Okay.
Bye.
Isn't your brother not going to school?
He can't just stay at home
and muddle along.
Now it's all computer assignment
based on registered residence.
It's not easy to transfer, right?
Why not go to the school
in his registered residence?
He...
doesn't want to go there.
Poor study?
Not really.
He's just naughty and lazy.
About the laziness in human nature,
it's a long story to tell.
I'll go feed the horses.
Goodbye.
I...
I'll check about the hotel.
I'm leaving, too.
Your tea is very delicious.
Thank you.
There are no rules for external things.
But the heart needs to achieve emptiness.
Definitely.
Uncle.
Eating alone?
Let me add a dish for you.
And this bottle of red wine.
My good friend sent it to me.
Let me share it with you.
Why are you here?
Xiaxia is going to Shanghai.
I was thinking.
What if he irritated you?
I have to come and see you.
I knew you are not really so nice.
You came to make fun of me, didn't you?
No.
I just came to drink with you.
The foreign wine, I'm not used to drinking it.
Wine glowing in the luminous jade cups.
Drinking to Pipa songs, we are summoned to fight.
Don't laugh if we lay drunken
on the battleground.
How many warriors ever come back safe and sound?
There was wine in Tang Dynasty.
How come it becomes a foreign drink?
Come on.
Taste it.
Taste.
Not bad.
Horse urine is better than it.
Drink it yourself.
I knew you might not get used to it.
Try this.
Cherry wine made by Aunt?
Great.
Wonderful.
Yao, let me tell you.
At that time,
you were young.
You must not remember it.
I was young then.
I have over a dozen woodcarving masters.
Their craft was awesome.
At that time, every family built houses.
They all came to us.
People from the village
and outside the village
all came here to find us.
The orders never stopped.
They had to wait in line at the gate.
The end of the line was out of sight.
The family who wanted the children
to learn woodcarving
always gave me wine, meat, fruits,
snacks or something.
That never stopped, either.
When did we need to
beg someone else?
It's all people coming to us.
My son said that
it's different now.
It's all machine carving.
Cheap and fast.
People are replaced by machines.
Most people in the future
will be replaced by machines.
The government asks me to pass the tradition on.
Nobody wants to learn it.
Even if someone learns it,
well,
the work in the future
is all done by the machines.
It's not working.
Not working.
It's not all true.
What this machine can do
is always the most basic thing.
It can't replace people.
Because it can't create things.
Can the machines make your reliefs?
Good things won't be replaced.
But if no one knows them,
no one appreciates them,
they will disappear slowly.
So we need to promote them,
and to publicize them.
Let more people know about this thing.
So they can like it.
Have you ever been to our embroidery workshop?
I won't go.
Those online stuffs are messy.
I can't stand it.
Both you and Master Huailan accept apprentices.
Then why does she get more apprentices
while yours ran out one by one?
♫ Listen to the rain
falling into the silent forest ♫
♫ Enjoy the mountainous landscape at sunset ♫
♫ The raindrops on the roof
fall into the eyes secretly ♫
♫ The world is like a quiet island ♫
♫ The sky is turning bright silently ♫
♫ Waiting for the seabirds
to call forth the ripples ♫
♫ Waiting for the sunlight to shine into
my heart across the lake ♫
♫ Set sail when it's windy ♫
♫ The reflection of clouds, the changing moon
and the stars all over the sky ♫
♫ The lost footsteps will be gradually erased ♫
♫ The light and shadow of four seasons ♫
♫ I've seen the meteor
that lights up the night sky ♫
♫ When the wind rises,
the sky will be cloudless ♫
♫ The sky is turning bright silently ♫
♫ Waiting for the seabirds
to call forth the ripples ♫
♫ Waiting for the sunlight to shine into
my heart across the lake ♫
♫ Set sail when it's windy ♫
♫ The reflection of clouds, the changing moon
and the stars all over the sky ♫
♫ The lost footsteps will be gradually erased ♫
♫ The light and shadow of four seasons ♫
♫ I've seen the meteor
that lights up the night sky ♫
♫ When the wind rises,
the sky will be cloudless ♫
♫ Go to a windy place to meet you ♫